MATEUS FERREIRA WEB DEVELOPER

mateusferreira0704@gmail.com	
in https://www.linkedin.com/in/mateus-ferreira070/	4/
https://mfladeira-eight.vercel.app/	
https://github.com/mfladeira	
Prazil	
+55 24 98126-5187	

Profile

Graduated in Software Engineering with 3 years experience in front-end and full-stack web development, I have skills in frameworks such as React, Angular and Laravel. I have experience working with UI components libraries, global state management, and Git/GitHub. I am knowledgeable in testing methodologies such as Jest, and experience with databases, such as MySQL. My adaptable and analytical thinking allows me to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate effectively in a team setting.

Hard-skills

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React.js
- Angular
- Testing (Jest)
- Accessibility
- Laravel

DelOffshore

- Global State Management
- HTML5 / CSS3
- UI Components Libraries
- Git / GitHub

Soft-skills

- · Analytical Thinking
- Adaptability
- Time management
- Teamwork

Work Experience

- Developed custom landing pages using HTML + SASS + JS that meet the specific needs of each client.
- Created an application for desktop using Electron + React + TS to automate the entire process of generating reports, reducing the time required by 30%.
- Developed a web application using HTML + SASS + JS to generate a PDF based on the information of the service provided. With this implementation, collaborators no longer needed paper to write the service information, reducing costs by \$100 monthly

 $React.js \cdot HTML5 \cdot CSS3 \cdot SASS \cdot TypeScript \cdot JavaScript \cdot Electron$

Front End Developer - Ímpar

Jan 2022 - Apr 2023, Brazil

May 2023 - Currently, Brazil

- Played a key role in developing the front-end side for an internal messaging system connecting staff built using React + .NET. This system was utilized by more than 60,000 users, enhancing communication and collaboration within the organization.
- · Successfully implemented a new feature that allowed teams to create surveys using adaptive cards, streamlining the feedback gathering process and improving overall efficiency
- Utilized Agile methodologies and collaborated closely with teams to ensure timely and efficient delivery of projects.

React.js · HTML5 · CSS3 · SASS · TypeScript · JavaScript · Scrum · Bootstrap · Syncfusion

Full Stack Developer - FGS

June 2020 - Dec 2021, Brazil

- The application aimed to connect distributors, installers, and sellers so they could buy and sell from each other, without the need to resort to other tools.
- Successfully integrated several third-party APIs, including Inter bank, Juno bank, and an API for issuing invoices, resulting in improved efficiency and automation of key business processes.
- Worked closely with the product team to understand requirements and provide technical input, resulting in a better alignment between business objectives and technical solutions.

React.js · Angular 10 · HTML5 · CSS3 · SASS · TypeScript · JavaScript · Laravel · MySQL · Angular Material

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering, Universidade Católica de Petrópolis

Jan 2016 - Dec 2020, Brazil

During my Bachelor's degree, I gained extensive knowledge and practical experience in various aspects of software engineering, including software development, data structures and algorithms, computer networks, and software testing. I also had the opportunity to participate in several group projects, which honed my teamwork and communication skills.

Web Developer, Le Wagon

Apr 2022 - Sept 2022, Brazil

I completed a rigorous and comprehensive full-time web development bootcamp at Le Wagon, where I learned modern web development practices and technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, and React.js. The program also emphasized the importance of project management, collaboration, and communication skills in the tech industry.

Languages

Portuguese - Native speaker English - Advanced